1200 F. California Blvd. MSC 605, Pasadena, CA 91126

□ (+1) 757-585-0632 | ■ gavin@caltech.edu | 😭 www.gavinmccabe.com | 🖸 gavinmccabe | 🛅 gavinmdev

"If something's important enough, you should try even if the probable outcome is failure."

# **Summary**

I'm a researcher and software engineer pushing the boundaries of human understanding to advance the frontier of physics and computer science. I have experience in quantum information science, nanofabrication, professional software engineering, and team management that can be applied to a variety of projects and disciplines.

# Work Experience \_

CURRENT DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE

Sept. 1, 2021

MG Venture, LLC.

Yorktown, Virginia

CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER

Aug. 2020 - Present

- iOS and web development team lead
- Acted as project manager responsible for delegating tasks, conducting code reviews, and providing feedback to developers and other partners
- Managed contracted companies and communicated with overseas partners.
- Oversaw beta testing of the Hangr iOS application to 15 various testing locations around the country

Gnosko Associates, Inc. Williamsburg, Virginia

CONSULTANT

Sep. 2021 - Present

- Provided subject matter expertise and training support to the U.S. government and private industry training programs, requiring demonstrated
  proficiency, while operating in both classroom and field training environments
- Required to maintain strict adherence to corporate and customer robust and exacting standards of performance while managing and delivering complex, time-sensitive training exercises that simulate real-world situations

## **Caltech Division of Computing and Mathematical Sciences**

Pasadena, California

Sep. 2020 - Present

TEACHING ASSISTANT

- CS 001 Introduction to Computer Programming
- · CS 004 Fundamentals of Computer Programming
- CS 132 Web Development
- SA 016 Cooking Basics
- Assisted students through both in-person and virtual office hours and graded assignments
- Helped students grasp the fundamentals of computer science in CS 001 through the introduction of Python
- Introduced students to functional programming in OCaml in CS 004, teaching basic functional paradigms
- Helped create assignments and code submission and review tools for a new course on Web Development (now labeled CS 132) teaching the basics of JavaScript, Express, Node.js, HTML, and CSS

### **Amazon Web Services Center for Quantum Computing**

Pasadena, California

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEERING INTERN - QUANTUM

Jun. 2022 - Sep. 2022

- · Worked with the control stack team
- · Assisted in creating software to support the mission of creating a usable quantum computer at AWS
- Attended various seminars, trainings, etc. to support my learning in quantum computing and software engineering in a professional environment

#### **Caltech Division of Computing and Mathematical Sciences**

Pasadena, California

HEAD TEACHING ASSISTANT, INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER PROGRAMMING (CS 001)

Sep. 2021 - Jan. 2022

- Assisted professors with onboarding new teaching assistants
- Graded assignments using various tools (including codepost.io, custom testing scripts, and style checkers) and provided detailed feedback to students
- Handle administrative tasks such as grading in-lecture coding assignments, assigning graders to specific assignments, and assisting professors
  during lecture

# Research

### Effect of Aluminium Fluoride Surface Layer on Waveguide Resonator Dielectric Loss

Pasadena, California

CALTECH MINNICH GROUP Feb. 2022

- Developed new cleanroom techniques to minimize dielectric loss in waveguide resonators, leading to a longer coherence time of qubits
- Simulated the replacement of various oxides on the surface of resonators with aluminum fluoride to reduce dielectric loss in the resonators

### Simulation of the Effect of Geometry on Transmon Qubit Dielectric Loss

Pasadena, California

Caltech Painter Group Oct. 2021

- · Collaborated with postdoctoral researchers to research the affect of dielectric loss on the cohesion time of transmon qubits
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Used COMSOL} \ to \ simulate \ various \ qubit \ geometries \ and \ the \ affect \ of \ various \ sources \ of \ dielectric \ loss$

## Numerical Monte Carlo Simulation of Cryogenic Buffer Gas Beams

Pasadena, California

CALTECH HUTZLER LAB

Jun. 2021

- Mark Reinecke Summer Undergraduate Research Fellow
- · Created Julia-based simulations to simulate the affect of cell properties on cryogenic buffer gas beams
- · Developed open-sourced wrapper for existing Python simulations in Julia which allow for a runtime that is 1000x the previous runtime.

#### Machine Learning Based Morphological Classification of Type-Ia Supernova Host Galaxies

Pasadena, California

CALTECH AND THE OBSERVATORIES AT THE CARNEGIE INSTITUTION FOR SCIENCE

Jun. 2020

- Shirley and Carl Larson Summer Undergraduate Research Fellow
- · Used CyMorph parametrization of type-la supernova host galaxies to develop automated classification pipeline
- Developed machine learning algorithms and neural networks for the Carnegie Supernova Project

# **Education**

Caltech Pasadena, California

B.S. IN PHYSICS Oct. 2019 - Jun. 2023

#### The Governor's School for Science and Technology

Engineering Strand Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2019

York High School Yorktown, Virginia

Honors Graduate Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019

### The College of William & Mary

Williamsburg, Virginia

Hampton, Virginia

COURSE AUDITS

May 2015 - Jun. 2017

Audited math courses pre-calculus through ordinary differential equations

## **Honors & Awards**

2022	Mark Reinecke Quantum Summer Undergraduate Research Fellow, Caltech	Pasadena, California
2020	Shirley and Carl Larson Undergraduate Research Fellow, Caltech	Pasadena, California
2019	Alden & Genevieve Roach Scholarship, Caltech	Pasadena, California
2018, 2019	Intel Excellence in Computer Science Award, Tidewater Science and Engineering Fair	Norfolk, Virginia
2018	Second Place, I/ITSEC Future Leader's Pavilion	Orlando, Florida
2018	Second Award of Excellence, Tidewater Science and Engineering Fair	Norfolk, Virginia
2018	Rensselaer Medal Award, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute	Troy, New York
2016	Third Place, Virginia State Science and Engineering Fair Engineering Category	Lexington, Virginia
2015	Member, Mensa Honor Society	Yorktown, Virginia

## Skills

**Programming** Python, C++, C, Swift, Objective-C, Java, MATLAB, Mathematica, OCaml, Julia

**Laboratory** Semiconductor etching, photolithography, metal deposition, SEM, AFM, microfluidics

Web Development HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, mySQL, SQLite, Bootstrap, Ruby

**Data Analysis** Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Astropy, Microsoft Excel, Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow

**Writing** T<sub>E</sub>X, Microsoft Word, Apple Pages, scientific writing

Flying Private Pilot Certificate